A lot of people now have said, "That's
it. The bear market's over." I don't see
the data on that yet. Because
historically it takes a year. A year
from the top
>> Mhm.
>> to the bottom. That has been one of the
most consistent things in cycle
behavior. Bitcoin spring happens the day
of the halving. That's it's the shortest
season always. Bitcoin summer uh the
period of time from the initial all-time
high for that cycle until the bubble
pops has always been between 9 and 11
months. Bitcoin fall is the day that the
bubble pops and the day of capitulation
where you hit the the low for that trend
is the beginning of Bitcoin winter. The
one that's not prevailed three times out
of three is 35 months from the bottom to
the top. Three times in a row now. There
is a big debate about whether the
four-year cycle is dead. And a lot of
prominent figures from Raoul Pal to
Arthur Hayes said it's only going to be
always up from here. We're not going to
have any cycles anymore or we're going
to have a five-year cycle. They were
wrong.
>> If institutions already know there's
this cycle, why can't they prep for it?
>> Because they deny it. And usually the
whales they tend to sell about four to
six weeks before the top and they tend
to wait until about four to six weeks
after the bottom. Cuz
the way I was able to confirm that was
nobody left to sell. And that's when the
the whales said, "I think it's time to
buy in big."
>> I did my math, it would be 44k to 38k.
>> Correct.
That could be an FTX-like moment. Um
perhaps this time there could be a wave
of bankruptcies.
>> So we shouldn't be rushing to buy now?
>> Um I would say
>> He's one of my favorite guests. The
crypto godfather, Michael Terpin is
here. Welcome back.
>> I'm delighted to be back, Bonnie.
>> You are the founder and CEO of Transform
Ventures and co-founder of Bit Angels.
Also, you have a very very popular book
called The Bitcoin Supercycle. Um we're
going to talk about that
later. But um just when I invited you to
be on the show this time you said, "I'm
happy to follow up." And as I predicted
more than a year ago in the book, the
bubble popped.
>> Yes.
Well, last year there was a big debate
about whether the 4-year cycle was dead,
and a lot of prominent figures from
Raoul Pal to Arthur Hayes said,
and the head of
some of the ETFs said, "Oh, it's only
going to be always up from here. There's
not going to be any crashes. It's all
about institutional investment. We're
not going to have any cycles anymore, or
we're going to have a 5-year cycle."
They were wrong. So far, everything that
has been the gist of the 4-year cycle
has proven true.
Once again, this has been every time, we
popped the bubble in the fourth quarter
of the year after the halving. That may
end up modifying to late third quarter
the next cycle because we've been
getting the halving earlier and earlier.
For example, the 4-year cycle isn't
actually a 4-year cycle. It's been about
a 46-month cycle. Otherwise, the halving
would always be on January 3rd, the the
Genesis block. Instead, the first one
was about 47 months afterward. We then
had a disruption in mining from China
banning miners in 2016, and that ended
up like modifying the block timing so
much that we went all the way from
November all the way up to July. So,
that ended up being about a 44-month
cycle. And then we had a 46-month cycle
when it went to May, and then this last
time a 47-month cycle when it went to
April, and we're projecting 2028 is
going to be in March. So, another 47. We
may actually get a point where we get a
48-month cycle cuz it is flexible.
>> Could you tell us more about the Chinese
mining ban you were just talking about?
>> Sure.
Um
that had a bigger effect in 2016 than it
did this last time.
And that was basically people were
scrambling to set up new mining
facilities, which ended up being largely
in Texas at scale. And so, Um, I
described in the book in the chapter on
mining, um, Satoshi did not make it a
4-year cycle. He made it every 210,000
blocks
* 33 cycles to distribute all the
Bitcoin. And it was timed so that it'd
be roughly every 10 minutes, but the
actual timing has to do with the
difficulty level, has to do with, um,
the mining strength. And when all of a
sudden the mining dropped, it ended up
making the blocks close a little bit
quicker. And that ended up speeding up
when the 210,000 block came.
>> You have a post on February the 10th,
you said a legendary trader who's been
in the market for 50-plus years said
Bitcoin sell-off is isn't random, is
organized.
>> Right. That's Peter Brandt, who's been,
you know, legendary tradfi,
investor and trader, and also has made a
lot of comments
on the crypto markets.
There've been a lot of comments about
institutions and what their trading
means.
And one of the things that it is worth
structure trading now. So, in other
words,
when we had the, the 1010, Black Swan
event, um, and then after that we had
the death cross. And one of the large
market makers, um,
we know who it's rumored to be, but it
was certainly a market maker who was
selling at scale in a structured format.
When you're selling between 9:00 a.m.
and 5:00 p.m. in New York time, that's
kind of structure. That's not random
retail panicking.
>> Mhm.
>> And so we saw that. And so institutions
basically mean you're going to see a lot
more kind of 9:00 to 5:00 weekday
trading as opposed to, you know, D Jones
will trade anywhere and anytime. And so
that has been an effect. Another, um,
effect that was interesting was this
last, uh, bear market, you didn't see a
lot of the selling on chain. So, the
effect of derivatives has been a lot
more pronounced because of the
institutional involvement.
>> So, what you're saying is institutions,
they sold first and then retail kind of
followed?
>> That's correct.
>> Right.
>> they followed the charts, right?
Everybody follows the charts, but uh it
you know, in many ways um what happened
on 10/10 kind of
accelerated the charts.
>> Mhm.
>> I mean, I knew that it was going to be
another fourth quarter. Didn't know
exactly when. There's several different
models to say which month it would be.
Some of them favored um October. Some of
them favored December. And um
you know, it's interesting the one
that's now prevailed three times out of
three is 35 months from the bottom to
the top.
>> Mhm.
>> And um
three times in a row now.
>> What happens if we didn't have 10/10?
>> Well, if we didn't have 10/10, we were
trying to break through the resistance
around 125
>> Mhm.
>> literally since inauguration day when we
didn't quite break through 120. And then
in the summer, you know, we had that
liberation day that brought us all the
way down to 75k. I tweeted at the time,
"That's it. We're not going to go any
lower until uh the cycle's over, and
it's not over." Uh cuz Bitcoin summer,
uh the period of time from the initial
all-time high for that cycle until the
bubble pops, has always been between 9
and 11 months. Did not make sense to me
that it would be so short.
>> Mhm.
>> Um similarly, when people said um
after 10/10 and it dropped all the way
down to 80k and then bounced, many
people were saying, "That's it. That's
the end of the bear market." I was like,
"After 6 weeks? Are you kidding me?"
>> Were you disappointed?
>> I was disappointed that it didn't get to
the midpoint of my projections from a
dollar point, which I said would be
about three times the having price plus
or minus macro.
>> Mhm.
>> Um the first two halvings were pretty
much spot on what it should have been,
100x and then 30x. I was projecting 10x
plus or minus macro for the 2020-2021
bull market. And the macro was
definitely bad. You had you had the
Biden administration crypto, Gary
Gensler, Liz Elizabeth Warren, etc. And
you also had a rapid rise of interest
rates that kind of, you know, crushed
any kind of continuing risk-on
investments.
Here, a lot of people were hopeful that
the Trump administration would pass the
Clarity Act. Genius Act was less
important. I mean, it was good, but it
didn't really affect the ability of
institutions to really start
recommending
digital assets, particularly Bitcoin, to
their
to their clients, right? And so, with
that not happening and now that it's
become sort of a midterm
football, it's probably not going to
happen, um in my opinion, unless they
force it through with a 51-49 vote in
the Senate. Um you basically have a
situation where the main macro was
Trump's tweeting about the tariffs left
and right. That's what caused the
Liberation Day crash on on traditional
markets as well, but it recovered much
much quicker and is now at an all-time
high for the S&P. But, you know, as sort
of the newest asset class, it's much
more sensitive to news.
And
you know,
the 1010 tweet that basically said 100%
you know, tariffs on China, by now
people should know that Trump doesn't do
what he says. He's just using it as a
bargaining chip. But, you know, there's
been a lot written about and I didn't
say this. I basically am just reporting
what others have said was that it was
pretty contrived. A lot of players knew
that the tweet was happening cuz they
acted so quickly. Um Morgan Stanley, for
example, um is alleged to have sent out
um you know, memos to their to their
brokers and saying sell Bitcoin, sell
MicroStrategy minutes before the tweet
came out.
>> No way.
>> Yes. Uh this reported a few places. And
also,
um Binance, whether it was Binance
Holdings itself or just big whales on
Binance started selling immediately when
the tweet happened. And then,
this is this is definitely not only
widely reported but seems to be correct.
Auto deleverages its market maker,
something they'd never done before.
Meaning that most market makers are both
long and short to protect their
positions. All of a sudden they're naked
longs when the world's on fire.
>> Let's talk about Bitcoin for now and
later we might go to Ethereum and other
asset class.
>> Sure.
>> Bitcoin bear market drawdown decrease
every cycle. First bear market 94%, 87%,
84, 77. And right now are we expecting
some somewhere between 65 to 70%
drawdown?
>> I was expecting that
um based on us topping out.
>> Yeah.
>> Um because we, you know, didn't just
come a little below my projection but we
literally only doubled instead of
tripled.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I could see it being um
a softer percentage but certainly over
50% and we've already been there. I mean
we hit from 126 down to 60 and bounced
off of that and a lot of people now have
said that's it. The bear market's over.
I don't see the data on that yet because
historically it takes a year.
>> Mhm.
>> Um the last three times it was a year
exactly four years ago. It was a year
minus three days four years before that
and it was a year and a couple of weeks
the very first having. And so just like
I didn't think it made any sense for the
bear market to be six weeks. I don't
think it makes a lot of sense for it to
be only four months.
Um that would disrupt a lot of other
things going forward particularly if one
of the predominant um you know,
thesis points of a what's happened so
far is the 35 months from the low. That
would really be a very short um bull
market and so something would have to
give like maybe a shorter spring.
>> So when you say a year, a year until we
hit the bottom or a year
>> A year from the top Mhm.
That has been one of the most consistent
things in cycle behavior.
>> So, we shouldn't be rushing to buy now?
Is that what you're saying?
>> Um I would say look at the charts. Um we
haven't really had any super bad news
yet. You know, cuz if you look at the
the last cycle and most of the
you know, bad news as I mentioned in my
book gets accelerated in terms of its
impact in a bear market and ignored in a
bear bull market. And the good news gets
ignored in the bear market. And so, um
you know,
last uh cycle, the first thing that kind
of dropped us heavily was uh the Terra
Luna crash. That brought us down and
we've been in the high 60s, bounced
around, had a little dead cat bounce
into We were still 50K after the first
quarter. I mean, that was, you know, 5
months almost uh after the halving. And
people were thinking, "Oh, we're going
to keep going up." The people didn't
believe in the cycles.
I was up. And um of course, the Terra
Luna crash brought us back to reality,
brought us under 40K. Um then it was
kind of struggling around a little bit.
At that point, I knew it was over.
I mean, I kind of knew it before, but um
and then the day that Celsius uh
announced that they were um you know,
closing off deposits and withdrawals, uh
uh-oh. Um it was around 30 then and
dropped down to 20 very quickly. And
people thought that was the bottom. And
um
but the whales weren't starting to buy
back. And usually the whales, they tend
to sell about 4 to 6 weeks before the
top.
>> Mhm.
>> Um they did this time as well. And um
they tend to wait until about 4 to 6
weeks after the bottom cuz they're
expecting a lower low. And you know,
after FTX happened, that was the bottom
and I knew it was the bottom. I I didn't
think it was going to go below It had
already went not only below the 200-week
moving average that we've always uh gone
below in a bear market, um but it also
went almost to the 300-week moving
average. And there are there are people
tweeting at the time, "I've got my buy
orders in at 5K, at 2K." It wasn't going
to go down that low. And uh sure enough,
that ended up being the market bottom.
And the way I was able to confirm that,
uh even though I was placing orders uh
you know, right after FTX, was when the
next shoe to drop in the bankruptcy
parade was um Genesis Lending. Um they
were a big bankruptcy. The price of
Bitcoin did not drop.
>> Ah.
>> And the reason is because there's nobody
left to sell. When there's nobody left
to sell, you were I mean, all the
short-term holders that If you didn't
sell after Terra Luna, you didn't sell
after um Celsius, and you didn't sell
after FTX,
you just become a Congratulations,
you're now a long-term holder. You're
not going to sell even lower. And so,
with all the short-term panic puppies
out of the way, um
price couldn't drop. And that's when the
the whales said, "I think it's time to
buy in big." And I knew a couple of
whales personally who had DM'd me and
said, "I'm about to make my biggest
Bitcoin buy ever."
And sure enough, it was all all up from
there.
>> Would you announce that on Twitter?
>> Um sure, I'll announce when I think the
bottom is in.
>> [gasps]
>> Well, if you look back, would 10/10 be
the first bad news?
>> Well, 10/10 was sort of a I called it a
black swan.
>> Mhm.
>> Um and I thought it was because it was
something nobody expected that tweet. Uh
nobody expected uh Binance to deleverage
market makers. Nobody expected to, you
know, go down that fast. I mean, we're
still a fairly fragile market in terms
of the size of of the market in that one
single market maker, it looks like,
could just put in massive sell orders
over 5 days and drive the price down to
the point where buyers didn't matter. I
mean, if they had done it another 10
days, we could have been all the way
down into the 50s.
>> Mhm.
>> I mean, at some point I think you would
have a reaction because they don't have
unlimited Bitcoin. At some point they
run out of Bitcoin that they needed to
sell to save their collateral and other
assets, but
>> We talked about the drawdown might be
65% to 70. And I did my math, it would
be 44k to 38k.
>> Correct. I don't think we're going to go
go down below 42.
>> Mhm.
>> Um because again we we did have a um a
low a lower a considerably lower high.
We had a slightly lower high last time
and we still ended up doing 75%.
Just yesterday, I know this will air a
little bit later, um BlockFi sells, um
which is a major TradFi player that also
is very heavily involved in Bitcoin
options. Um these are yeah I have
friends there personal friends there. Um
I talked to them a few weeks ago,
nothing seemed wrong. They ended up like
suspending withdrawals.
And they said, "We're working on
liquidity issues, etc., etc." But, you
know, historically in crypto,
when somebody says they're suspending
withdrawal, bankruptcies are right
around the corner. Not saying this is
going to happen with BlockFi sells, but
they did $61 billion last year. So, what
collateral damage would be if they can't
get their deposits back at all and
there's no money.
Um so, that could be an FTX-like moment.
Last time all the bad news seemed to be
around Bitcoin lending and collateral
damage when they lent it to say FTX.
It's a lot of them did. Um perhaps this
time there could be a, you know, sort of
um
a wave of bankruptcies. I'm not saying
it's going to happen, but it could
happen if say we go down to 45k. And um
there are, you know, sort of um
uh derivatives um exchanges that played
with their own money, played with
customers' money. I mean, this is a this
is what happens with centralized uh
companies sometimes. And if that
happens, people will panic, they'll
start withdrawing out of all the
derivatives exchanges, which could be a
self-fulfilling prophecy about them then
limiting withdrawals. And that would
that would probably lead to the bottom.
And it's interesting how the bottom
always happens during the bear market
that is always in, you know, starts the
third quarter of the year after the
having and I would contend that the
bankruptcies don't cause the bottom of
the crash. The bear market that's
predictable by the cycle causes the
bankruptcies that then accelerate and
find the actual bottom.
>> If institutions already know there's
this cycle, why can't they prep for it?
>> Because they deny it. The majority of
them is saying the cycle is dead. I'm
I'm having a talk later this afternoon
on that that the topic.
Um you know, Matt from
uh Bitwise ETF has been saying cycle's
dead, only up from here. Uh it's now
going to look like an institutional
asset class. It'll look like gold,
silver, stock market. And um
you know, the the I'd say more people
say that the cycle is irrelevant than
say that it still controls thing. And
I'm you know, one of the lone voice in
the wilderness saying,
you know, look at the math, it's still
controlling things.
>> But my question is if everyone is saying
it's over and institutions don't really
care about this cycle,
they are the big money. They shouldn't
really control the supply and demand.
>> not the big money yet. I mean Yeah, if
you look at certainly holdings, whales
hold a lot more than
than than
than institutions. Institutions are
still dipping their toe in cuz
institutions typically are not buying
and selling. They're they're
they're using derivatives, right?
They're they're using the ETFs. They're
using
you know, long and short on the ETFs cuz
they get much better margin on the stock
than they do on the asset itself. And so
there's a lot of levels of obfuscation
what's really going on. But last I
checked the overall Bitcoin asset class
was only 20% derivatives and 80% spot
trading.
Traditional markets are the are the
reverse. They're 80% derivatives.
>> So when institutions buy, except for of
course Saylor, but other people are
buying derivatives. They're not actually
buying the Bitcoin. is that what you're
saying?
>> Um that is correct or a a combination
where the ETFs, which are controlled by
institutions, are by and large bought by
retail.
>> Mhm.
>> Right? So, [clears throat] they're
telling, you know, newbie retail, "Hey,
it's safe now to buy." The ones that
said, you know, it was, you know, Ponzi
scheme when it was $100 or $1,000. Now,
they're getting commissions and they're
like, "Hey, this is You should put 5% of
your money into this or 1%." And um
so, the way the ETFs work, um
you know, they only trade during market
hours and they have to settle before the
next market, but the institutions have
hold of that capital. They're hedging
the positions, right? And so, they, you
know, first of all, just on fees alone,
um IBIT is the most profitable uh part
of uh the entire BlackRock empire.
>> There's another tweet. History rewards
patience, not panic. And last time we
talked, it was May 2025. I asked you if
it was always a good time to buy
Bitcoin, you said, "Nope."
And I love that cuz this is a different
answer from everybody else.
>> Well, yeah, um dollar cost averaging
works most of the time, but it doesn't
work on the way down. Um because then
you're just um dollar cost averaging to
a lower low. I think dollar cost
averaging if someone has a certain
amount of uh disposable income every
month, yeah, buy from the bottom all the
way up, but but accelerated during the
times when you make the most money. I
would say that you just hold it, hold it
in, you know, interest-bearing accounts,
hold it in gold. Even hold it in uh you
know, one thing that I think is a a
great uh investment in terms of just
cash, um particularly for people in
taxable jurisdictions in the US, is what
Michael Saylor's done with his S T R C.
He actually has it structured as return
of capital. So, you're going to get, I
think it's now 11.25%. He just raised it
again. I mean, that's like almost three
times what T-bills are paying in money
market accounts. And um
you'll go in
I think their ex-dividend date is like
Friday and the price goes up a bit and
then it goes down whenever the price of
Bitcoin goes down.
I missed buying in
last week cuz I didn't have a buy order
on it with my broker but it actually
dipped into like around $94 to get in.
That's an extra 5% interest right
effectively if the if it's if it's $100
and
it's brilliant in that you know, anybody
that says that Saylor's going out of
business when Bitcoin hits a such and
such point hasn't followed the structure
of his investments. I mean these are all
stocks that can stop paying dividends,
can can amend the dividends but as long
as he's paying really high dividends and
keeping a lot of it in cash to pay the
dividends, I don't see how even if
Bitcoin goes down to $20,000, he'll just
buy more Bitcoin cuz his thesis is that
Bitcoin's going to go up 21% a year for
the next 20 years
and he's getting capital around 10% you
know, that math works out.
>> I know we talked about the four seasons.
Could you repeat that for people that
have might not have watched the previous
one?
>> Sure. Satoshi in the white paper
said that as long as the amount of
new Bitcoin bought every four years
exceeds the amount mined, the price has
to go up. It's supply and demand. And so
far that has been absolutely true. The
first halving was $12.70.
The second halving was $670.
The third halving was $8,700.
And the fourth halving was $63,900.
Always up.
>> Yeah.
>> And as long as we have more new Bitcoin
bought than Bitcoin mined, which is a
tiny amount now, it's it's scarcer than
gold in terms of its
annual inflation rate at 0.8%
versus gold is around 1 and 1/2.
Uh my goal a little bit higher because
the price of gold means that you can,
you know, you can spend more money
mining. So some stuff that was not
profitable at 2,000 will now be
profitable at 5,000. Um so that
basically is um um is is is what Satoshi
said and it's been true.
The wild volatility that scares, you
know, retail investors away, but it's an
opportunity if you understand it, um
comes from fear and greed. And I had
identified going back to 2015,
um
you know, that there were repeating
patterns and they've completely repeated
every time. And four behaviors based on
fear and greed that happen in the exact
same order and they've they continue to.
And I named them after the four seasons.
So Bitcoin spring happens the day of the
halving. That's in one day, minor
profitability goes from being roughly
maybe 10 to 20% profitable
to then you have half the rewards and
the same expenses. Now you're losing 30
to 40%. A number a number of them will
just turn off their machines, especially
in the old days. Now they typically have
secondary sources of funding. They've
got bank loans. They're public
companies.
But they still will use that as the time
to upgrade their machines because
they're losing money. Unless they've got
like, you know, stolen electricity or
something, um they are losing money. And
so the algorithm adjusts downwards so
that if there's fewer people mining, um
you know, or fewer, you know,
hash power mining, um it'll adjust to
make sure that the blocks still come
through roughly every 10 minutes.
And between that going down and just
simply demand going up, it starts to go
up slowly, but largely it's flat. This
last time Bitcoin spring was 7 months,
that's the longest ever. It's the
shortest season always so far.
First one was 4 months, and that is
between the time of the having and the
time they have a new all-time high.
Literally 6 months in, it was flat. It
was
63,900
the day of the day of the having, April
19th of 2024. 6 months later it was
still 64,000. It had gone down a little
bit, you know, I think that was the time
of like Germany selling, yen carry
trade, stuff like that. It had gone it
had
started to bounce off of 70 as
resistance. The number they had to hit
was 73,850.
That was the new all-time high of the
prior cycle, even though it was only a
month before. A number of pundits again
and proven wrong, and I I literally
re-edited my book as it was going to
press to address the fact that there was
a new all-time high a month before the
having. Cuz again, the the pundits same
pundits that were saying the cycle's
broken now were saying the cycle's
broken then. Oh, well, how can you have
a cycle if you have the new all-time
high a month before the having?
That's the new That's the new high and
it should have been a year after the
having.
Well, you can't have a new high before
the having for this cycle. That was last
cycle. By definition, what it did do,
and I was correct in projecting this, it
reset the bar of what you needed to
cross. Before that happened, as soon as
you got above 68,000,
you'd go into Bitcoin summer. Now you
had to go into 73,850.
I projected in my book that if Trump
won, that'd be good macro, and it would
happen early November. And because the
strength of it happening eventually, and
happening early, was strong enough, if
Kamala won, it would still happen in
late December. We won't know what
happened if Kamala won cuz she didn't,
but Trump won, and the new all-time high
was on on day itself, November 5th.
>> Mhm.
>> I also projected that if that happened,
we would have 100,000 by by early to
mid-December, and we did.
And it kept going up until uh the sell
the news on uh inauguration day when we
almost hit 120, and then we were flat
for up and down and you know, down to 75
and then up to 126 for the almost the
rest of the year. And that was the thing
that we couldn't break was that 120
five-ish plane. And um you know, and I I
I submit that the the biggest reason was
because of uh uncertainty over the
tariffs.
>> And right now we are in
>> We are in fall.
>> Mhm.
Um maybe a prediction on the next
>> Sure.
>> four years.
>> Yeah, so to finish the seasons, Bitcoin
fall is the day that the bubble pops,
begins it, and the day of capitulation
where you hit the the low for that trend
is the beginning of Bitcoin winter.
Number of people have have you know,
kind of used the phrase euphemistically
crypto winter mean mean anytime people
are depressed and the price is down, but
my Bitcoin winter is actually a
a time that you should be buying because
that's when [clears throat] the price
all the short-term uh you know, holders
have have fled, and the price is not
going to go down any further, so it has
to go up. And um on a long-term basis,
the best time to buy every single cycle
has been Bitcoin winter the last day of
Bitcoin fall. Sold within 20% of the
high cuz you're never going to catch it
exactly, although I have friends who
caught the exact day a couple times. I
caught the exact day a couple times. Um
but and and then bought back within 20%
of the bottom. And the bottom takes a
longer time to play out
>> Mhm.
>> because it just stays down there
everybody thinks Bitcoin's dead. We've
already started the Bitcoin is dead
headlines, by the way. Financial Times
last weekend said Bitcoin at 60,000
that's still 60,000 too high. It then
bounced back to 70, they had to change
the headline. Um Peter Schiff came out
said it's going to zero roughly. Um you
know, we hadn't heard from
Nouriel Roubini in a while. He came up
and said it's like useless. And so, when
it gets into the 50s or even 40s, then
you're you have CNBC and CNN also saying
it's dead and it's going to zero. And
that's the best time to buy. The best
time to buy on a daily IRR basis is the
first day of Bitcoin summer because it
goes up so quickly. Um, so, you know,
again, dollar cost averaging, you're
better to, you know, kind of hold some
of those dollars and deploy them at the
start of Bitcoin's summer and then again
at the start of Bitcoin winter. All your
money is made if you're not just holding
forever, um, by properly identifying the
top and bottom of Bitcoin fall and, uh,
again, my my my
analysis was that
if you bought a thousand Bitcoin at the
first halving,
$12,700, most investors can afford that.
Um,
and, um, just held it until today,
whatever it's $67,000 today, so you'd
turn your 12,000 to 67 million. Still
beats every other asset class.
And if you sold, you know, on, uh, you
know, around 10, 10 or before, um, you'd
have 12,000 to 120 million. It's like
10,000 X. Selling within 20% of the top
and buying within 20% of the bottom, and
obviously the first cycle is the
hardest. Um,
at the top, you would have had over 7
billion dollars cuz you would have had
60,000 Bitcoin.
Because you would have sold at a
thousand instead of 1,200 and then
bought back around 250. Now you got
4,000 Bitcoin. Four years later, similar
thing, you'd have 16,000. Four years,
wouldn't exactly have 64,000, you'd have
about 60. I think going forward, we're
not going to be 4X by by by timing it,
uh, correctly, but I think that you can
be around 2X for the next two cycles.
And particularly if, um, the super cycle
kicks in. So, the super cycle is when
the diminishing returns that we've had
so far in the four seasons, um,
is overwhelmed by the S-curve of
adoption that happens to every new
technology. We're only 4% of the world
has any Bitcoin, and yet we're 95% mined
out. When it's 20%, 30% of the of the
world having at least, you know, one
Bitcoin,
where's that Bitcoin going to come from?
It's not going to come from the miners.
>> Do you still think Bitcoin is a new like
a very new asset class that people are
still very interested in because there's
AI now? It seemed like the new kid,
right?
>> AI is not an asset class. It's the
technology and the asset class would be
equities. Equities for AI, which is a
sub asset class of equities.
Um
certainly AI is the new shiny kid on the
block, and Bitcoin goes through
different cycles than AI AI does. Um
there was a little bit of panic that AI
was going to cause the next big global
crash. I mean, there's a lot of people
who feel that.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and but right now it's all happy
land, right? I mean, it's all all-time
highs.
Um you know, I was offered I I've done
some investments in AI even though I'm
mainly crypto and then some, you know,
real estate, etc. Um but uh
you know, I um I was offered um
by a friend of mine who got into the
Anthropic, whatever it was, C or D round
a couple years ago. I think it was only
about 2 years ago when it was 400
million, and I was like, "Do they have
any revenues?" Well, not really. Are
they making money? They're
losing money like crazy. And I was like,
"I'll pass. 400 million seems a little
little pricey.
Um you know, I'm not used to that as
somebody's largely a seed investor."
Boy, that would have been a thousand X.
This their latest round is like over 400
billion.
>> Mhm.
>> So, it's been insane numbers, and we'll
see whether it keeps up when people
invest the 400 billion, whether these
all are trillion-dollar companies.
>> See, that's the thing. Like, because AI
has these crazy returns, now retail
investors are like, "Why Bitcoin? Why
not that?"
>> And absolutely, and the other one is, of
course, is precious metals. And again,
retail
in all these asset classes jumps in at
the high and gets burned because they
buy in at the high. They're the ones
that bought gold at $5,500 on leverage
and then, you know, pulled back. So, I
think gold and silver Um I mentioned
this in my book, actually. I quoted the
CME as saying that, you know, their
definition of a super cycle is something
that is a fundamental change in the
nature of the commodity that lasts for
at least 5 years. And they saw
two super cycles in the last 100 years
in commodities. The first one was in the
'70s when um you know, Nixon took us uh
the US off the gold standard. Um and
also allowed Americans for the first
time in 40 years to buy gold. So, you
all of a sudden had a new reason to buy
gold and you had a new class of
investors that could buy gold. Went 4x
in the in under a decade. The second one
was when China just started buying
commodities volatile because of its
rapid expansion industrially in the
'90s. And that, you know,
skyrocketed the price of nickel, of
copper, and that's so much gold and
silver, but other, you know, kind of
commodities that are actually used in
commerce. That was the second super
cycle. And it and they had said during
COVID that too early to tell, but we may
be entering a third super cycle based
on, you know, ballooning uh uh
uh
fiat debt and uh distrust in um sort of
the debase the monetary debasement
trade.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh had I read my own book, I might
have got a bought bought a little bit
more gold when it when it came out. Cuz
obviously that was a good trade to to
make in uh you know, 2024.
>> Well, a lot of people were talking about
the debasement trade last year, 2025.
And Bitcoin was in being included in one
of the asset class you should buy. But
everything else went up and people are
dis- disappointed with Bitcoin's
performance.
>> they didn't look at the cycles, right?
So, you don't buy at the top of the
cycle.
>> Yeah.
>> retail does cuz they see their friends
making money. Um you buy at the bottom
of the cycle. There's this uh classic
like New Yorker style cartoon from the
last cycle
that had two lines that had a little
table that Bitcoin for sale at the
$60,000 people are lined up around the
block. Bitcoin on sale $15,000
nobody was nobody was buying. And that
that's repeating and you know you wonder
why people
you know if it's so obvious they don't
do it. It's again fear and greed. This
last $60,000 price
fear was the highest ever. It was higher
than FTX.
It was five. FTX was seven.
They got to remember four years ago
$60,000 was bull behavior. Oh my god
it's $60,000 it's going to the moon.
So the four years difference the
expectations of the asset class are so
amazingly high that people are planning
when it's $60,000.
You know
is a saying if in doubt zoom out right?
And if you look it still is
you've only had a 1% chance of losing
money throwing a dart at at buying
Bitcoin and selling it five years later.
And you're not forced to sell if it was
that 1%. And it's more reliable if you
basically only buy in the the bear
market.
>> We talked about the possible low. What
about the possible high? I it's very
early to predict the next high but
>> I think next time is the first time that
we have a serious shot at a super cycle.
And we had a theoretical shot this time
but since it was the first time
institutions were in they were able to
do things like for the first time really
offer
gigantic monetary numbers to whales who
want to sell a little bit a little bit.
I mean say you're a whale that you know
working a normal 9-5 job and you know
mined Bitcoin when it was two cents and
they have 10,000 of them. And they've
been a hodler right? And maybe they've
loaned a little against their Bitcoin
watching it go up in value so they were
able to buy a home but not a fancy home.
Now all of a sudden you know
Galaxy he
and says hey we've got
Michael Saylor who wants to go and buy
blah blah unlimited amounts of Bitcoin.
Um
will you sell it at 120?"
You know, and the wife's going like,
"How much is that, honey?" Oh, it's
about a billion and five. You want to
sell half? You can buy it back later.
And so, it's certainly not that whales
decided that they're out of Bitcoin,
right? As a tradfi guy who now talks a
lot about Bitcoin said it was Bitcoin's
IPO moment and so the early founders
sold. Chris, they didn't sell
everything. Um and
but with the founders of like Facebook,
they don't necessarily buy back. They'll
kind of get, you know, additional
vesting or something on new shares. But,
you know, the whales, if you look on
chain, they do buy back. They sell at
the top and they they do exactly what I
recommend. They sell at the top and buy
back at the bottom. So, say you're a
whale, there's one whale wallet that was
tracked. It was a large number like
15,000 Bitcoin or something like that.
He sold a good chunk of them.
Um at least it moved into Kraken and
then kind of disappeared. If he did
sell, he'll buy back, right? I mean, if
you sell a billion dollars worth and you
know, you're able to buy back at a half
or less, you know, you have the same
amount of Bitcoin and now you've got a
half a billion dollars to go and buy
whatever, you know, you and your family
want to buy, a private jet, you know,
etc.
>> Can't you take a loan against your
Bitcoin?
>> You can, but you make more in terms of
absolute return if you sell at the top
and buy back at the bottom. And
obviously a lot of this depends on
on your tax situation, but if you're in
Puerto Rico, it's zero capital gains. If
you're in Hong Kong, if you're in
you know, Singapore, there's a lot
Dubai, there's a lot of places that have
wealthy people who do not pay capital
gains and so to me they're leaving money
on the table if they don't follow my
system.
>> Um I talked to a few
Bitcoin miners from the US and they were
talking about how they cannot really
control the supply anymore because right
now the block rewards are so little.
>> Well, they never were able to control
the supply. It's uh built in code.
>> 7,200, and then now, you know, 3.125
Bitcoin.
>> Per 10 minutes.
>> Yes.
>> So, it's 450 a day.
>> Mhm. 450 a day, that is
>> available.
>> Well,
okay, last year, Saylor would buy
a year's supply in a month, right? So,
>> He did that this time, too. I think he
bought
20,000
Bitcoin in
the first first month. I can't remember
the exact number, but yeah, it was if
not a year's supply, it was a lot. I
mean, 450 a day, you know, times 365.
So, no, right now, the institutions are
buying far more than the miners are
putting out. So, that's why
one of the reasons why people say the
cycle's dead is, "Oh, well, it's such a
small, trivial amount now." Well, it's
not a trivial amount trivial amount
compared to the buying. If no one was
buying, yeah, it would be a trivial
trivial amount, but you have to look at
the ratio between, you know, the
available Bitcoin going down and the
amount being bought going up. So, that
is diverging along the lines of what
Satoshi talked about. Over a 4-year
period, if the amount being bought
exceeds the amount
being mined, the price has to go up, and
it will go up, you know, I can
project with almost absolute certainty
that the price of the next halving in
'28 is going to be above the price in in
'24. '24 was 63,900.
I'm thinking it'll be at least double,
and it could actually be, you know,
approaching 200,000.
I do believe that, I'll call it out
here,
for the second time ever, I believe
we're going to have a new all-time high
prior to the next halving.
>> Which will be when?
>> Next halving is
is 210,000 blocks after the last
halving, projected right now to be in
late March.
So, it could be early April, it could be
mid-March. As we get closer, it becomes
more definitive Um, in terms of you
know, are there mining disruptions that
speed it up or there you know, something
that that that slows it down. But if
it's mid March,
you know, I
I foresee that we'll have a new all-time
high, you know, not in '26 but in '27.
>> How does election play into this?
>> That's part of macro.
>> Mhm.
>> Right. And it's interesting because I do
not think as I mentioned in my book and
I think I said on your show, I don't
think it was an accident that Satoshi
shows the election year for that for
that the likely having dates.
And so far it's been an election year
every time. You know, first one was '12,
'16, '20, '24. Next one will absolutely
be '28. If you're moving up, you know,
even a month at a time, that means in
another you know, three four cycles will
break that and it'll be just before in
fact
if you go and even get into early
February, you won't even have had the
first primary. So
we'll we'll see how that impacts. But
what that means is that your bear market
typically has fallen during the
midterms. And uh
unfortunately, this has now become
only one party that supports crypto.
It used to be you know, stand with
crypto has done a great job of uh
literally crypto was the
primary industry
in the last election in terms of
donations. More than the big banks and
big pharma combined which was
unthinkable four years ago.
And um
but since most of it went to people who
supported crypto and Kamala was very
fuzzy. I mean, she basically said, well,
I I I I I'm looking at crypto because I
understand it's a way that black men can
make money or something like that. It
was very you know, identity based
instead of like saying no, it's it's
good for the economy. The Democrat
midterm talking points now being Trump
should be impeached because you know,
he's grifting off of the asset class
that his family's making money on. We're
not going to vote for any kind of uh
legislation in the Clarity Act until,
you know, Trump addresses his family's
holdings. So, they've made they've
they've sort of taken the Clarity Act
hostage over their midterm election, you
know, talking points. And, you know,
it's right now it's considered to be
75-80% of the Democrats win.
That's the end of uh crypto legislation
for the next 2 years because the House
is in the United States what controls
new legislation. They will not propose
any alternative to the Clarity Act
unless it is going backwards. In fact,
the so-called compromise I I Act which
the banking lobby largely wrote was,
"Hey, let's compromise. Let's have DeFi
be illegal. Only broker-dealers can do
it. Let's have uh self-custody be
illegal. You know, you have to go to,
you know, a TradFi custodian. Um and
let's uh make sure that there's never
any interest or rewards on stablecoins
cuz that takes away from the banks."
That is worse than we have now, and
that's why Brian Armstrong said, "I
can't support this. It's worse than
nothing at all." And so, that will be
the rules for the next couple of years
if the Democrats win the midterms, which
is why it's important if you're a crypto
voter in the United States, um
regardless of uh what your local person
is, um to to vote uh
the the the red button uh which is the
orange button right now.
>> You talked about DeFi stablecoin. Why is
Clarity Act important for Bitcoin,
though?
>> Because the Clarity is everything else
but stablecoins. It basically is we have
clarity of regulation.
Gary Gensler during the last
administration said Ethereum was a
security.
I mean, in here they've at least said
informally, you know, David Sacks has
said, "Well, you know, there's
commodities, there's securities, and
there's um collectibles. And
collectibles don't need regulation. The
Trump coin was a collectible. Meme coins
are collectible." Under Gary Gensler, he
was inferring that, you know, everything
was a security except for Bitcoin.
>> Mhm.
>> And um huge divergence, right? The
investment banks that are the Morgan
Stanleys, the people who can, you know,
take their trillions of dollars of uh of
of clients that they advise, they're
like, "We don't know what to tell them.
Uh will they be, you know, fined for
buying Ethereum cuz this is a security
and they are not an accredited
investor?" I mean, and um so clarity is
just to simply say,
"What are the rules?" And right now
there's a pro-Bitcoin
uh chairman of the SEC, uh Atkins, and
there's a pro- uh crypto um
you know, new head of the uh CTFC. And
their positions are very reasonable.
They're like, you know, only securities
are securities, right? And the
securities are are it's how you define
this thing called the Howey Test from
the 1940s that is, you know,
very vague in terms of like, I mean,
most people think of securities as
something that you own, you know, a
stock or some other instrument where you
getting dividends, you're you're relying
on the um
uh the statements of the company, their
projections, their their
etc. You know, I I call it the gold bar
versus gold mining stock.
>> Mhm.
>> A gold bar, even if Peter Schiff says
gold is going to the moon, he doesn't
control the price of gold. No one person
does. It's supply and demand.
I feel the Bitcoin and and most of the
altcoins are in that same camp. Whereas
a gold mining stock, if you say, "Hey,
our stock's going to the moon. We're
about to find a new supply of gold."
That is a forward-looking statement that
investor relies upon and can be held
accountable for if they're if they're
making it up. You know, rules and
penalties for making uh statements of
public companies.
>> Mhm.
>> Um whereas if you're just talking about
the price of Bitcoin,
that's a commodity.
And I don't control the price. If I say
Bitcoin is going to 400,000 last time
and it doesn't, I can't be sued by
somebody who bought Bitcoin.
You know, I'm not making financial
advice. I'm just telling you how I see
it and how I'm playing it.
>> You launched a Bitcoin Supercycle hedge
fund and you outperformed Bitcoin by
2.5% in your first month.
>> Correct.
>> What type of strategies are you using?
>> I'm using the ones in the book. By and
large, it frustrated me that when I
would tell, you know, people to buy
Bitcoin and they didn't want to go and
open a Coinbase account and they said,
"Hey, is there a stock I can do?" Yeah,
there's an ETF now, but if you want to
beat the price of Bitcoin, you should
look at a at a manager and I was looking
to see what funds out there were were
only Bitcoin and were beating the price
of Bitcoin and I didn't find any.
>> Mhm.
>> And the the the best known ones, I won't
mention their names, but they're, you
know, very very large names uh that are
in the crypto space. In 2024,
I think the returns were like 47% and
52%, which is phenomenal if you're a
stock market investor, but if you just
held Bitcoin in your wallet, it was 120%
and then they historically get creamed
during the the bear markets. And that's
because even though they employ some,
you know, chart analysis and algo
trading, they they they look at their
sharp and sortino ratios. They're much
more conservative and you're not going
into your Bitcoin investment all in of
everything you own. You're looking to
beat the asset class.
If the top-performing S&P hedge funds
did not beat the S&P, they'd be out of
business.
>> Yeah.
>> And so that's not the case in Bitcoin
yet and so we're hoping to be, you know,
kind of one of the first ones that uh
outperforms Bitcoin uh after fees.
>> So you are in charge of the strategies.
>> I am. I'm the chief investment officer.
>> Nice. Earlier we talked about the next
high. I would like you to break it down
to bull case, bear case, and
uh base case.
>> Sure.
The bear versus the bull versus the base
largely depends on whether we have
supply shock in 2029.
So in other words, 2029 is It's to be
the next bull market is the year after
the halving. And um um
supply shock is when you literally run
out of coins to sell. Um the only time
that really has happened in the past was
in October of 2013.
I mean, widely reported and I found this
to be the case, too, that you just you
couldn't buy Bitcoin. You wanted to buy
a lot of Bitcoin. Coin Coin uh base just
was unavailable. They were like, "Oh,
we're having outages, etc."
Rumor was that they just had didn't have
any coins to sell. They had more
requests to sell Bitcoin to buy Bitcoin
than to sell. And so, that will happen
at some point. I mean, we have very low
numbers historically of what's on the
exchanges, particularly during the bull
market.
>> Michael, we would love to hear your
prediction.
>> My range of where the halving's going to
be is worst case, I think, maybe 120,
best case, maybe 200. And then, if you
look at diminishing returns that had
been 100x the first cycle, uh 30x should
have been 10x was eight, should have
been 3x was two.
You know,
I would think the next thing on that
sequence might be around 30 to 50% uh
gain above the the halving. So, if it's
you know, so that would be a range of
maybe 180,
which would be very bearish, to uh
perhaps uh 400.
And
that's before you consider the super
cycle.
>> Could you also share the timeline as
well?
>> So, the timeline would be, again, the
four seasons, right? Bitcoin spring will
be in um
roughly March of 2028. Bitcoin summer
typically has been four to seven months.
It's been a little expansive. So, that
would mean that it might be in October,
November.
Um you know, probably late third, early
fourth quarter of 2028, when you then
pass the all-time high. Except, you
know, we're probably going to have a new
all-time high prior to the halving. So,
it'll be the all-time high of even if
it's the day before the halving. And you
know, the the halving is typically the
fair market price of Bitcoin. So, the
last time even though we went up to 73,
we went down to the fair market price.
So, let's say the fair market price is
next time is like, I don't know, 150 or
something like that. Um that means that
if we're at 180, we'll probably dip back
down to 150 at the halving. So,
if it's 150, you know, if we double it,
that's going to be 300, right? If we
only go up 50%, that'd be 225. But, the
super cycle effect is when during
Bitcoin summer, so like you then hit
that all-time high from the prior cycle.
So, you say your halving price is 150,
and the the high prior cycle was one,
you know, 170. It could be a very short
time frame until it hits that again. So,
let's say it hits it as early as um you
know, I don't know, May or June of 2028.
>> Mhm.
>> Typically 9 to 11 months until you pop
the bubble. And so, that then factors
into a lot of the things of what was the
bottom and the 35 months historically.
So, you have to look at all that data
and see which one is the strongest to
repeat. Because off every cycle, there's
always been two things that have always
happened,
and they can't both happen again because
they it's either or. And so, those are
the things that we'll find, but Bitcoin
summer is when the bubble pops, and
that's when the demand is the strongest
from retail. Oh my god, it's going to a
million dollars. I better buy in before
it hits a million, and then it only hits
400,000 and the bubble pops, and then
they cry and you know, they don't buy
back in at the bottom, which would be
say maybe half the price of the top. So,
um supply shock is when, you know, like
in October of 2013,
there's no more coins to sell. I mean,
there's people trying to like pry it out
of the hands of the whales, and they're
like, you know, I'm going to wait for
higher price. I'm not going to sell to
you for 400. Can you Can you give me
500? And so, you can have a a god candle
at that point, when all of a sudden, you
know, the price of Bitcoin goes up from
like 300,000 to 400,000 in a week. And
that's when a lot of retail is going to
buy in. Oh my god, like they are with
gold and silver right now or or before
that bubble uh popped a little bit. And
um you know, and that's when you have
this super cycle effect. So that it
kicks off this
You can't unsee the high, right? So if
we're at 480, all of a sudden the
expectation of the next um cycle being a
million becomes much more realistic than
if we only get up to 200. I mean, if you
look at the big fud story that kind of
like is credited in part for why we hit
60K,
it was because Jeffrey Epstein bought
Coinbase shares.
And um
>> And he's supposed to be to Satoshi.
>> Yeah, and that's even more ridiculous,
right? I mean, um he just because he
gave a half a million dollars to MIT um
of which a portion went to the digital
currency lab, which paid uh Gavin
Andresen's uh salary,
does not mean he's Satoshi. I mean, this
was like five or six years after uh
after Bitcoin and um you know, it
mentioned in um
in uh in in in the latest batch of
files, um the person who probably orange
peeled uh Epstein. And that was around
11, 2012, I think. And uh so how can you
be orange peeled, you know, years after
the white paper and be Satoshi?
So there's absolutely no evidence he's
Satoshi, but I'm sure short sellers
calling the media and saying, "Hey, do
you know Epstein is Satoshi?"
>> I haven't asked this question for a very
long time, but why aren't people asking
who he is or she or they?
>> They are constantly, but we don't have a
definitive answer. I mean, there's a lot
of I'd like to know. I mean, I'm
probably happy that I don't know because
uh
you know,
they could be
sitting in a jail cell on trumped-up
charges.
Right? I mean, uh look what happened to
the uh uh
the founder of WikiLeaks.
You know, they could say, "Oh, you
created something that was used for
money laundering. We have to have a
congressional hearing." And so,
you know, it's uh it's probably a good
thing that there's no definitive proof.
I mean, Craig Wright, not an American
citizen, uh but obviously can be
indicted anywhere, declared he was
Satoshi and then a court said, "No,
you're not." That doesn't mean he
wasn't.
>> Mhm.
>> I mean, there's a lot of evidence to say
that he was part of the early Bitcoin um
um you know, mining and um that he might
have been one of
one of many people who collaborated to
be Satoshi.
Although, it's interesting that Martti
Malmi's um
you know,
recently released about a year or two
ago uh emails with Satoshi cuz he was
the 19-year-old college student that um
emailed Satoshi cuz Satoshi's white
paper had an email, contact me, and he
did. He's like, "Hey, I'm a college kid.
Uh
I What can I do to help? I can make
websites." And so, he did help with, you
know, bitcoin.org, which was Satoshi's
uh website, and uh bitcointalk, which is
his chat group, and got paid in Bitcoin.
But, he also said, "Well, the first
thing you can do is turn on your
computer and start mining so that
there's at least two people mining at
all time."
>> Mhm.
>> So, unless he was trying to throw people
off the scent that there was other
people involved in Satoshi,
that would be saying, "I'm one person."
And certainly, it was a consistent voice
in all the writings of Satoshi to make
it sound like it was one person. Um so,
it's still a mystery. I mean, some
people think it's Adam Back. There was
an HBO special saying it was Peter Todd,
which I think was the least likely. And
that was all based on something he said
and made a mistake in quoting something
and and referenced something that was
before he got into Bitcoin. It was
crazy.
>> Well, I assume you have, you know, quite
a big investment in Bitcoin. And I've
talked to um institutions and they're
like, if there's a even a very small
chance that there's a quantum risk or
like the Satoshi who is Satoshi risk,
they would has it be very hesitant to
put in more money, but you're not.
>> No.
Um, I think the quantum risk is
extremely low
because of a couple of factors. Number
one,
I think right now the top cubits in the
world is like a hundred or something and
it's going to take about
20,000 cubits to potentially break one
wallet address.
>> Mhm.
>> Why would they not go after the bank
where they can go and get a lot more
money from a centralized, you know, kind
of system that they could just drain
money left and right. They'd go after JP
Morgan before they go after Satoshi.
And again, let's say North Korea says
we're going to target breaking Bitcoin
and going after Satoshi's wallet.
Where are they going to get the hardware
from? It's not just software and this is
very closely guarded, can't be exported.
I mean, right now the only people who
would be able to go and theoretically do
this are like Google and IBM.
You think they're going to go rogue and
try to steal things? I mean, I don't
think so.
That's number one. Point number two is
that we have a long time. I mean, it's
not going to be next year that they get
to that level of cubits.
Five to 20 years I think are the the
estimates. I think let's say it's 10.
Um,
10 years from now, we have there's
already a lot of teams working on
quantum secure wallets, quantum secure
forks. Now, if it's a if it's a quantum
secure fork, that means that the old
wallets that you they've lost the keys
would be vulnerable.
But I don't know if that's the worst
thing in the world. That means you
actually would have 21 million Bitcoin.
Right now you probably only have about
16 million that are accessible.
Um,
presuming that
something that's never moved is lost.
>> the worst case?
>> It's it's a it's an opportunity. Like
say someone sold cracked Satoshi and
sold all their Bitcoin all the way down
to like $50. I'd be buying at that
point. Because that means that that risk
now is out of the way. It's been
distributed to a lot of other holders.
>> I understand that, but people wouldn't
be buying at 60k.
Now, if they know that might happen.
>> Um I think the odds are very low of that
happening.
As in for the reasons I said, but
again, I
think it would be a blip and it would be
much higher in the future after that.
So, you typically either have, you know,
two philosophies. Either you're a trader
or you have a fund that's trading for
you. I mean, we're an algo-based
fund. So, I'm the chief investment
officer, but I have a team of algo
developers and traders. So, we are doing
things every month based on, you know,
what we see as, you know, 5% or higher
moves within the channel or breaking the
resistance. But, the big moves are, you
know, buying as much as possible at the
bottom and selling as much as possible
at the top. But,
no, I think that you you'd see it coming
a long way out. And again, I believe
that
the industry will find
solutions to it for everything but maybe
Satoshi's wallet. And again, who is
going to crack it? It's not going to be
Google, and I don't see how North Korea
ends up getting all that hardware that
is banned from export and building I
mean, I guess if they can build nuclear
weapons, maybe they can build a
supercomputer and steal the Google code,
but uh
I I don't see that as a big risk. And if
it happened, they would go after the
banks first. What's going to happen to
JP Morgan stock or the Bank of America
if all of a sudden they get like
billions of dollars drained overnight?
I guess they get propped up by the Fed.
Um which is already printing too much
money. So, there's other hypothetical
risks out there that I don't I don't I
don't lose any sleep at night about
Bitcoin going
you know, down to $50 cuz I'll buy more.
>> I think a lot of young people they want
a target to know I'm working towards
however many Bitcoin. What is that
number if they are in their 20s or early
30s?
>> average person should just make sure
they have one.
I mean because
>> I mean one Bitcoin if you're in your 20s
and you expect to retire in your 60s,
you got 40 years for Bitcoin to go to uh
Well, we'll see with fiat the basement
what a million dollars is actually worth
in the future, but you know, I think
sailor's base coin base
position in 20 years is about 13 million
a Bitcoin. So, I think most people
you know, middle class uh expectations
and background could easily retire on 10
million.
>> Mhm.
>> And um maybe 10 million's only worth 5
million. They could usually that's still
considered that's still an accredited
investor. It's a qualified investor. Um
you know, it's not 30 million is ultra
high net worth. So, you know, if you got
one Bitcoin and you're going to be
retiring in 40 years,
I mean I I can't imagine that Bitcoin is
going to be worth less than 10 million
in 40 years.
So, um one Bitcoin, you know, should be
generate intergenerational wealth. If
you can do better and again during the
during the bear market when people are
running away from it, if it gets down to
50,000, you know, do what you can to I
mean I forget which investor said um on
the traditional thing, what do you do to
get rich? The first thing is do whatever
you can when you're young to get your
first hundred thousand dollars in cash
that you can invest in. That's where
you're going to start cuz if you're just
constantly just living paycheck to
paycheck, you know, you're never going
to be able to invest in anything when
the opportunity comes along. If you get
your first hundred thousand, you can go
and buy a house and then rent that out
and buy another house. You can buy
stocks with that. You can do all sorts
of things that will compound over time
historically.
Same thing with one Bitcoin which is
less than a hundred thousand right now.
>> Did you just say in 30 years 30 million
will still be high net worth or is it
now?
>> Today it is. So, yeah, they'll probably
Well, you know, they haven't uh they
haven't changed the rules on accredited
investing. You know, they said they said
it was a million dollars 30 40 years ago
and they still say it's a million
dollars.
>> That's insane.
>> I know. A million is not quite Well,
that's good though because that means
more people who are upper middle class
qualify as accredited investors. You
know, they're they're looking under
Trump in particular to change the rules
that, you know, if you're bright, you
know the risks and you want to invest in
your friend's company that you think is
going to be the next Facebook. You
should be allowed to do that. You know,
and um you just sort of like a sign off
risk. Yes, I know what I'm doing. I I I
I I recognize I'm not being scammed,
blah blah blah. I mean, look, they let
people come to Las Vegas and bet their
entire life savings on red on a
blackjack table while they're drinking.
There's no SEC out there stopping them
from that, but they're stopping them
from, you know, investing in what they
think is the next Anthropic.
>> Wow.
That makes so much sense.
Well, if people want to talk to
uh Michael, you have an AI now.
>> I do. So, um
my book uh you know, is available on
Amazon. It uh is distributed by Simon
and Schuster.
Um
but the my publisher did not pick up the
uh audio rights yet or the translation
rights, but I had the rights in my
contract to make an AI version. And um
and so I did. And so, it's bitcoin
supercycle.ai.
>> Mhm.
>> Um it's uh it's a
$50 for a year. Um although I I I have
some codes that you can share with uh
the viewers um to make it lower, 40%
off. And um
basically includes uh the full audio
book in my voice that I did not have to
sit in a studio like most most authors
do for 12 hours reading and taking
second takes. I gave my AI provider
holo.ai um
two sentences of my voice and it sounds
like me. And so it's a full you know 21
chapter plus introduction of me reading
in my voice the audio book in English
and in eight other languages including
Chinese.
>> You are speaking Chinese.
>> I'm speaking Chinese. Yes.
>> That is insane.
>> Chinese. I'm speaking Spanish. I'm
speaking French in the proper accents.
>> So either they could read this book or
just go on the website and
>> and and have it read to them and they
can download it as well from from the
from Bitcoin Supercycle dot AI with a
subscription.
>> I love that. Thank you so much again for
coming on. It's always so much fun
talking to you.
>> Thanks Bonnie.